

INTRO

As a designer for the past 13 years, I have valued versatility above all else. I take pride in filling multiple roles on a given project, having the ability to work on identity, iconography, type, illustration, interface design, as well as front-end implementation.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts, Commercial Art

Millersville University, Millersville (Lancaster) Pennsylvania

SELECT CLIENTS

Temple University

SFMOMA

Best Buy

MLS

C-SPAN

Red Bull

MKBHD

Lifetime Television

Kennedy Space Center

Dave Mustaine

Wells Fargo

Best Buy

MKBHD

Letterboxd

Dave Mustaine Letterboxd

AC Moore Desus & Mero

Everlast Rogue NASA

Frigidaire Criminal Podcast

Burlington Coat Factory The Game Awards

CONTACT

570.212.9029

kyle.j.ruane@gmail.com

@kyleruane

EXPERIENCE

## Senior Product Designer, Cotton Bureau / 2017-Present

Officially entrusted with visual design and user experience of the consumer-facing e-commerce website, but also handled front-end development, company brand design and management, creation of concepts and visual assets for marketing campaigns, and product design for clients.

### Freelance Designer & Creative Consultant / 2006-Present

Full service designer for hire, working directly with clients as well as select contract engagements with product teams and agencies. Many different types of projects have found their way across my desk, including but not limited to web design, application design, logos and corporate identities, illustration, and icon creation.

### Co-founder & Creative Director, Plain / 2012-2016

Creative duties for a funded startup building a website-building platform called Barley, which included branding, marketing materials, pitch decks, app interface design, user experience, and transactional email design.

# Principal & Lead Designer, Argyll Studios / 2010-2012

Management and design vision for a small creative firm specializing in custom WordPress solutions.

## Design Lead, Solid Cactus / 2007-2010

Design for over 100 eCommerce stores for various platforms including Yahoo! Small Business, eBay Prostores, Amazon Webstores, 1Shopping Cart and other custom solutions while working with developers and project managers in a team environment. Also worked on logos, information-based websites and a number of internal products.

## Graphic Designer, Bailey Design & Advertising / 2005-2007

Worked directly with clients in designing various print materials and advertising/marketing campaigns, providing direction and creative solutions.

### **Art Director, Connections Magazine** / 2005-2007

Responsible for ad design and magazine layout, as well as creative direction for Connections Magazine, a large format local arts and entertainment publication.